Atmel Libraries
════════════════════════════════════════════════════════════════


Atmel Analog Companions
――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――
Description
Atmel Power Management And Analog Companion (PMAAC) ICs.

An integrated Analog Companion IC reduces board space and cost by replacing a number of discrete components. Its microcontroller
interface enables the MCU to optimize the system's power consumption. In particular PMAAC ICs integrate Power Supplies such as
Linear Regulators (LDO) and Switching Converters (DCDC) and Audio Interfaces such as a Stereo DAC.


Atmel Communication ICs
――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――
Description
Atmel Communication ICs.

This collection provides wireless industrial and consumer devices for automatic metering, alarm systems, and home control applications,
as well as toys and gaming applications. Also included are cordless phone ICs and IEEE 802.15.4-compliant devices.


Atmel CPLD Industry Compatible
――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――
Description
Atmel industry-compatible CPLDs.

The ATF15xx CPLD family offers standard power and ultra low-power devices, with densities ranging from 32 to 128 Macrocells (MC)
and operational speeds of up to 200MHz. These devices can be used for I/O expansion as well as for memory control – interfacing
with different types of memories such as Compact Flash or mobile SDRAM.



Atmel CPLD Proprietary
――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――
Description
Atmel proprietary CPLDs.

This collection features the ATF750C/CL and ATF2500C CPLD devices. The ATF750C has twice the logic of a standard 22V10 in a
pin-out compatible 24- or 28-pin package. It is ideal for those designs that need a bit more logic than is offered in a 22V10
device, but where the 22V10 pin-out must be maintained. The electrically erasable ATF2500C is a very high-density (2500 usable gates)
44-pin device. It replaced the ATV2500B/BQ/BQL/BL in commercial, industrial and military temperature grade offerings.


Atmel GPS
――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――
Description
Atmel ANTARIS4 family of GPS devices.

The Atmel ANTARIS4 GPS chipset, with its high-accuracy and AECQ-100 qualification, is perfectly suited to GPS applications within
the automotive industry.
The ANTARIS4 GPS chipset embeds an RF receiver and a baseband IC. The 16-channel architecture offers excellent tracking and positioning
accuracy and fast dynamic position tracking. The ANTARIS4-engine also features SuperSense™-enabled indoor GPS reception for dashboard
antennas, or assisted-GPS (A-GPS) reception. The devices also support U.S. WAAS and European EGNOS global positioning satellite systems.



Atmel Industrial Control
――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――
Description
Atmel industrial control devices.

This collection provides Atmel industrial control devices for AC and DC motor, temperature and illumination control applications.
Devices include:
  • Phase control devices with built-in load-current detection and feedback and overload protection
  • Sensor-controlled timers for advanced dimmer and motion sensor applications
  • Zero-voltage switches for controlling resistive loads at the mains, through use of a triac in zero-crossing mode.


Atmel MCU Wireless
――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――
Description
This collection includes Atmel's single-chip solutions and IEEE 802.15.4-compliant transceivers.

The single-chip ATmega128RFA1 combines an AVR microcontroller with a 2.4 GHz RF transceiver for IEEE 802.15.4 and ZigBee applications.
The high-performance IEEE 802.15.4 transceivers are low-power and support regional 700/800/900 MHz frequency bands available in China,
Europe and North America, as well as the 2.4 GHz ISM band available worldwide. All Atmel transceivers can be combined with their
AVR microcontrollers over SPI. Devices include AT86RF212, AT86RF230, AT86RF231, AT86RF232 and AT86RF233.



Atmel Microcontroller ARM
――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――
Description
Atmel ARM-based Flash microcontrollers and ARM9-based microcontrollers.

Atmel's ARM-based Flash microcontrollers are based on the ARM Cortex-M4, Cortex-M3, ARM926EJ-S and ARM7TDMI processors. They feature
up to 2MB of Flash memory and 192KB of SRAM, with operating frequencies up to 200MHz. In addition, the Cortex-M3 and Cortex-M4
based devices offer native QTouch support.
Atmel's ARM9-based microcontrollers are based on the ARM926EJ-S core, with operating frequencies up to 400MHz. They include a range
of high-performance peripherals, as well as providing DDR2, LPDDR and NAND Flash support.



Atmel Microcontroller AVR Automotive
――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――
Description
Atmel Automotive AVR microcontrollers.

This collection provides Atmel's 8- and 32-bit AVR microcontrollers, which are qualified for use in the automotive industry.
These devices offer complete system-in-package (SIP) solutions incorporating features and functionality such as:
  • An AVR microcontroller
  • LIN and CAN interfaces
  • Voltage regulator
  • Watchdog
  • Floating point unit (FPU)
  • FlashVault code protection
  • High-speed Ethernet
  • USB with OTG connectivity


Atmel Microcontroller AVR Battery Management
――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――
Description
Atmel AVR microcontrollers for battery management.

The ATmega range is a family of low-powered CMOS 8-bit microcontrollers based on the AVR architecture. The AVR Smart Battery family
of microcontrollers provides secure authentication, highly accurate monitoring and autonomous protection for Lithium-ion battery cells.
This collection provides a range of AVR microcontrollers dedicated to Li-Ion battery management for 1 to 4 cells in series. Designed
to maximize lifetime and energy per cycle, they include analog-to-digital converters tailored for battery fuel gauging and voltage
monitoring.
Features include:
  • High performance, low power Atmel® AVR® 8-bit Microcontroller
  • Advanced RISC architecture
  • High endurance non-volatile memory segments
  • A range of battery management features, including;
      ○ One to four cells in series
      ○ High-current protection (charge and discharge)
      ○ Over-current protection (charge and discharge)
      ○ Short-circuit protection (discharge)
      ○ High-voltage outputs to drive N-channel charge/discharge FETs
      ○ Optional deep under voltage recovery mode, allowing 0-volt charging without external precharge FET
      ○ Optional high-voltage open drain output, allowing 0-volt charging with external precharge FET
      ○ Integrated cell balancing FETs
  • A range of peripheral features, including;
      ○ configurable 8-bit or 16-bit timers
      ○ Serial Peripheral Interface
      ○ High resolution coulomb counter ADC for current measurements
      ○ Programmable watchdog timer


Atmel Microcontroller AVR UC3
――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――
Description
Atmel 32-bit AVR UC3 microcontrollers.

This collection provides Atmel's 32-bit AVR UC3 family of high-performance, low-cost microcontrollers. UC3 microcontrollers incorporate
native fixed-point DSP support, dual-port SRAM, a peripheral DMA controller and multi-layer, high-speed bus architecture. Intelligent
peripherals and dynamic power control make UC3 devices suitable for portable and battery-powered applications. Selected UC3 devices also
include an integrated Floating Point Unit (FPU) to improve arithmetic performance on decimal numbers.
Features across the device range:
  • Up to 512KB Flash
  • Up to 128KB SRAM
  • Up to 66MHz maximum operating frequency
  • 1.5 MIPS/MHz
  • Up to 16 ADC channels with 10- or 12-bit resolution and conversion speeds up to 2000ksps
  • Up to 4 DAC channels with 12- or 16-bit resolution
  • Up to 123 I/O pins
A0/A1-Series
――――――――――――
  Designed for high data throughput, low power consumption and computing performance, the A0 and A1 Series features high connectivity
  with USB device and host, Ethernet MAC and SDRAM interfaces. These communication features, together with fast flash and large
  internal SRAM, make it ideally suited for data-intensive applications.
A3/A4-Series
――――――――――――
  The AVR UC3 A3/A4 Series is designed for very high data throughput with Hi-Speed USB device and host, SD/SDIO card, Multi-Level-Cell
  (MLC) NAND flash with ECC and SDRAM interfaces. This series is well suited for applications such as audio, biometric, communication,
  USB to SDcard bridges and USB dongles.
B-Series
――――――――
  The AVR UC3 B Series is designed for high data throughput, and outstanding computing performance in space constrained applications.
  It is particularly suited for applications like USB Human Interface devices, USB stick gateway, biometric, bridging, industrial
  control, and low-power portable applications.
C-Series
――――――――
  The AVR UC3 C Series is designed for high performance industrial and automotive control applications, including fast communication
  hubs and motor control. The series offers a rich set of arithmetical and analog features.
L-Series
――――――――
  The AVR UC3 L Series is Atmel’s first picoPower® 32-bit microcontroller, and offers a wide range of innovative technical features.
  The series is ideal for battery-powered, portable consumer applications, board controller, game pads, remote controls, and human
  interface devices.
D-Series
――――――――
  The AVR UC3 D Series is an entry-level microcontroller that includes a hardware QTouch® capacitive touch interface, Full-Speed USB
  Device, RTC with calendar, 10-bit ADC, USART, SPI, TWI, PWM and I2S . The low-power UC3D embeds SleepWalking technology that allows
  a peripheral to wake the device from sleep mode. The QTouch® capacitive touch module supports up to 25 channels in hardware, and each
  channel can be configured as buttons, sliders and wheels. The Glue Logic Controller (GLOC) contains programmable logic and lookup
  tables that can be connected to GPIO pins, which can reduce the amount of external components.
Audio Series
――――――――――――
  Selected Atmel AVR UC3 32-bit microcontrollers are available in an Audio version and can be recognized by the AU letters before the
  dash in their part numbers. They allow the execution of Atmel licensed Audio firmware IPs.


Atmel Microcontroller AVR XMEGA
――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――
Description
Atmel 8/16-bit AVR XMEGA family of microcontrollers.

The AVR XMEGA delivers a good combination of real time performance, integration and power efficiency. This includes features like
a 128-bit AES and 64-bit DES cryptographic engine, high-speed analog modules, flexible Timer/Counters, multiple communication modules
and types, and efficient power management.
Features across the device range include:
  • Up to 256KB Flash
  • Up to 16KB SRAM
  • Up to 4KB EEPROM
  • Up to 32MHz maximum operating frequency
  • 1.0 MIPS/MHz
  • Up to 16 ADC channels with12-bit resolution and conversion speeds up to 2Msps
  • Up to 4 DAC channels with 12-bit resolution and conversion speeds up to 1Msps
  • Up to 4 analog comparators
  • Up to 78 I/O pins
All devices include the following communication interfaces:
  • USART – between 3 and 8 USARTs in a device, with up to 4Mbps data rate
  • SPI – between 2 and 4 SPIs in a device, with up to 16Mbps data rate
  • I2C – between 2 and 4 TWIs in a device, with 100kHz and 400kHz support
In addition, 100-pin devices feature an External Bus Interface (EBI), allowing for connection to external memory (up to 128Mbit SRAM
and 16MB SDRAM) and memory-mapped external hardware. Selected devices also incorporate a full-speed USB module.


Atmel Microcontroller megaAVR
――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――
Description
Atmel 8-bit megaAVR microcontrollers.

The MegaAVR family offers a diverse variety of 8-bit microcontroller devices, ranging from general purpose models to those that
incorporate specialized peripherals. These devices are well-suited to applications requiring large code bases, offering substantial
program and data memories, with performance up to 20MIPS.
Features across the device range include:
  • Up to 256KB Flash
  • Up to 16KB SRAM
  • Up to 4KB EEPROM
  • Up to 20MHz maximum operating frequency
  • 1.0 MIPS/MHz
  • Up to 16 ADC channels with10-bit resolution and conversion speeds up to 125ksps
  • Up to 1 DAC channel with 10-bit resolution
  • Up to 4 analog comparators
  • Up to 86 I/O pins
Different devices in the range offer varying communication interfaces, including:
  • USB with OTG connectivity
  • SPI
  • I2C
  • UART
  • CAN
  • LIN


Atmel Microcontroller tinyAVR
――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――
Description
Atmel tinyAVR microcontrollers.

Atmel tinyAVR devices are 8-bit AVR microcontrollers optimized for applications that require performance, power efficiency, and ease
of use in a small package. All tinyAVR devices are based on the same architecture and compatible with other AVR devices. The tinyAVR
is the most compact device in the AVR family and the only device capable of operating at just 0.7V.
Features across the device range include:
  • Up to 16KB Flash
  • Up to 512Bytes SRAM
  • Up to 512Bytes EEPROM
  • Up to 20MHz maximum operating frequency
  • 1.0 MIPS/MHz
  • Up to 12 ADC channels with 8- or 10-bit resolution and conversion speeds of 15ksps
  • 1 analog comparator
  • Up to 28 I/O pins
Different devices in the range offer varying communication interfaces, including:
  • SPI
  • I2C
  • UART
  • LIN


Atmel Multimedia
――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――
Description
Atmel multimedia devices.

A range of devices suitable for Multimedia and Home Entertainment applications. Includes IR Control Products
(U2538B - 20-60kHz frequency range, and insensitive to ambient lighting conditions) and Laser Driver ICs.


Atmel RF Identification
――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――
Description
Atmel RF identification devices.

RFID (RF Identification) involves contactless reading and writing of data into an RFID tag's nonvolatile memory through an RF signal.
Low frequency RFID devices typically consist of a transponder (tag) and reader.
This collection provides RFID devices operating within the 100-150kHz and 13.56MHz bandwidth ranges, including:
  • Atmel CryptoRF Reader (AT88RF1354) – high-performance ISO/IEC 14443 Type B RF Reader IC that communicates with RFID transponders
    or contactless smartcards. Operating at 13.56MHz, data is exchanged at half-duplex at 106kbps.
  • Atmel CryptoCompanion (AT88SC018) – providing host-side cryptographic security for embedded systems, working in concert with an
    Atmel CryptoRF Reader.
  • Atmel IDICs (U2270B and ATA5570) – low-frequency (100-150kHz) RFID Read/Write devices for contactless identification. The U2270B
    is a base station that uses a bidirectional interface to communicate between the transponder and microcontroller, amplifying
    the transponder signal and forwarding it to the microcontroller for decoding.


Atmel Security Smart Card
――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――
Description
Atmel secure Smart Card devices.

This collection provides intelligent hardware security solutions and AVR microcontrollers for smart card reader applications.
Devices include:
  • CryptoMemory family for high-security EEPROMs and host-side security for applications requiring comprehensive data protection
  • CryptoAuthentication ICs that can securely validate a wide variety of physical or logical elements in virtually any
    microprocessor-based system
  • FIPs-certified microcontroller-based security solutions that protect against cloning and counterfeiting


Atmel Serial EEPROM
――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――
Description
Atmel serial EEPROM devices.

Serial EEPROM devices available in 1Kbit to 1Mbit densities, 1.7-5.5V, and in I2C-, Microwire- and SPI-compatible protocols. The devices
come in a number of industry-standard package types, including DFN, VFBGA, SOT23 and WLCSP. Devices are optimized for use in automotive
and industrial temperature applications.


Atmel Smart RF
――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――
Description
This collection contains receivers, transceivers, transmitters and power amplifiers - all for RF applications.
  • Receiver ICs: The ATA8201 & ATA8202 are UHF ASK/FSK transparent receivers in a 5x5 mm QFN24 package. They support Keeloq® and have
    a receiving range of 313-317 MHz and 433-435 MHz respectively. The ATA8203, A8204 & AT8205 are industrial UHF ASK/FSK multi-chip
    PLL receivers in a SSO20 package supporting data rates from 1 to 10 Kb/s.
  • Transceiver ICs: The ATA5428 is an integrated UHF ASK/FSK multi-channel half-duplex transceiver with low power consumption in
    a 7x7 mm QFN48 package. The ATR2406 is a single-chip RF transceiver for applications in the 2.4 GHz ISM band - available as a
    QFN32 package.
  • Transmitter ICs: Highly integrated micro-transmitters with an AVR core. Designed for battery powered applications. The AVR controller
    simplifies design and achieves throughputs approaching 1 MIPS/MHz. Devices include ATA8401, ATA8402, ATA8403, ATA8404, ATA8505,
    ATA8741, ATA8742 & TA8743.
  • Power Amplifier: The T7024 is a Bluetooth/ISM 2.4 GHz front-end IC with power amplifier, low-noise amplifier and T/R switch driver.


Atmel SPLD Industry Standard
――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――
Description
Atmel industry-standard SPLDs.

This collection provides a range of 250 to 500 gate SPLDs (Simple Programmable Logic Devices), covering industry-standard 16V8, 20V8
and 22V10s, in a variety of voltage and power-saving options. Power options include: Low-voltage, zero-power, quarter power and the
proprietary "L" automatic power-down low-power devices. All devices are EE-based for high-reliability and easy re-programming.


Atmel Touch Solutions
――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――
Description
Atmel Touch Sensor ICs.

This collection provides Touchscreen controllers for tablets and handsets with touchscreens up to 15.6 inch, plus stylus capability.
Also includes Touch keypads and application-specific controllers for non-mechanical buttons, sliders, and wheels on touch-sensitive
devices.
