Microchip
════════════════════════════════════════════════════════════════


Microchip dsPIC30F
――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――
Description
Microchip 16-bit dsPIC30F Digital Signal Controllers.

dsPIC30F are 5-Volt Digital Signal Controllers offering up to 30MIPS DSP performance. They are based on a modified Harvard Architecture
with separate Data Bus and a 24-bit Instruction Bus for providing more Single Cycle Instructions. These DSCs support up to 4KB EEPROM,
motor control peripherals and an integrated CODEC interface.


Microchip dsPIC33F
――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――
Description
Microchip 16-bit dsPIC33F Digital Signal Controllers.

dsPIC33F are 3.3-Volt Digital Signal Controllers with up to 70MIPS DSP performance. These support up to 32 channel high-performance
10/12-bit ADCs, on-chip digital power, motor control and audio peripherals and integrated op-amps. These DSCs come with up to 2 CAN,
I²C, SPI and PMP, and are also available in extended and high-temperature options.


Microchip Interface
――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――
Description
Microchip interface devices.

This collection provides a wide range of interface devices across the following categories:
  • Real-time Clock/Calender
  • CAN communication
  • Ethernet
  • I/O expanders
  • Infrared communication
  • LIN bus transceivers
  • USB


Microchip I2C Serial EEPROM
――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――
Description
Microchip I²C-compatible Serial EEPROMs.

This collection provides I²C-compatible Serial Electrically-Erasable PROMs. EEPROMs are available with a capacity of up to 1Mbit.
These devices have a low-voltage design, which permits operation down to 1.7 Volts, thereby reducing standby and operating currents.


Microchip Linear
――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――
Description
Microchip linear devices.

This collection provides a range of Microchip linear devices in the following functional categories:
  • Operational Amplifiers
  • Comparators
  • Programmable-gain Amplifiers
  • Selectable-gain Amplifiers


Microchip Microwire Serial EEPROM
――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――
Description
Microchip Microwire-compatible Serial EEPROMs.

This collection provides Microwire-compatible Serial Electrically Erasable PROMs. EEPROMs are available with a capacity of up to 16KB,
and allow for clock rates of up to 3MHz.


Microchip Mixed Signal
――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――
Description
Microchip mixed-signal devices.

This collection provides a range of mixed-signal devices across the following functional categories:
  • Analog-to-Digital Converters (ADCs):
      ○ Successive Approximation Register (SAR) ADCs
      ○ Delta-Sigma ADCs
      ○ Dual-slope ADCs
      ○ Binary and BCD ADCs
      ○ Display ADCs
  • Digital-to-Analog Converters (DACs)
  • Digital potentiometers
  • Frequency-to-Voltage Converters
  • Voltage-to-Frequency Converters


Microchip PIC10
――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――
Description
Microchip 8-bit PIC10 microcontrollers.

PIC10 microcontrollers have a Baseline architecture, with up to 512 (x12-bit words) program memory and up to 24 Bytes of data memory.
Some offerings also feature 8-bit Analog-to-Digital Converters (ADCs). They have a 2-level hardware stack.


Microchip PIC12
――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――
Description
Microchip 8-bit PIC12 microcontrollers.

PIC12 microcontrollers are Flash-based, with up to 2K (x14-bit words) program memory and up to 384 Bytes of data memory. These are
offered in baseline, mid-range or enhanced mid-range architectures, and suit a variety of general-purpose applications. The baseline,
mid-range and enhanced mid-range core PIC12 devices have 2-level, 8-level and 16-level hardware stacks respectively.


Microchip PIC16
――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――
Description
Microchip 8-bit PIC16 microcontrollers.

PIC16 microcontrollers have up to 28KB program memory and up to 1.5KB of data memory. These are offered in baseline, mid-range or
enhanced mid-range architectures, and suit a variety of general-purpose applications. The baseline, mid-range and enhanced mid-range
core PIC16 devices have 2-level, 8-level and 16-level hardware stacks respectively.


Microchip PIC18
――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――
Description
Microchip 8-bit PIC18 microcontrollers.

PIC18 microcontrollers are based on the PIC18 architecture, and have up to 128KB program memory and up to 4KB of data memory. They
suit a variety of general-purpose applications. These microcontrollers have a 32-level hardware stack, and are optimized for
C programming.


Microchip PIC24E
――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――
Description
Microchip 16-bit PIC24E microcontrollers.

PIC24E are Flash-based microcontrollers, with up to 536KB Flash program memory and up to 52KB SRAM. These devices support features
such as:
  • Nine 16-bit timers
  • User-selectable 10-bit or 12-bit ADC
  • 3 comparators
  • Serial communication resources – UART, CAN, SPI, I²C and USB-OTG
Certain offerings may also feature auxiliary Flash, CTMU and RTCC. They suit a variety of general-purpose applications.


Microchip PIC24F
――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――
Description
Microchip 16-bit PIC24F microcontrollers.

PIC24F are Flash-based microcontrollers, with up to 256KB Flash program memory and up to 96KB SRAM. These devices support features
such as:
  • Up to five 16-bit timers
  • 10-bit or 10/12-bit ADC
  • Up to 3 comparators
  • Serial communication resources – UART with IrDA, SPI, I²C and USB-OTG
Different microcontroller offerings may also support features such as EEPROM, CTMU, RTCC, LCD, DMA, PPS, PMP, CRC, JTAG and a
Graphics display controller. They suit a variety of general-purpose applications.


Microchip PIC32
――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――
Description
Microchip 32-bit PIC32 microcontrollers.

PIC32 are 32-bit microcontrollers, based on the MIPS M4K core architecture. They operate at speeds of up to 80MHz with 1.56 DMIPS/MHz
performance. They have up to 512KB Flash and up to 128KB RAM for data and program execution.
These devices have extensive analog and digital peripherals including:
  • 10/100 Ethernet
  • I²C
  • ADCs
  • Serial communication peripherals
  • USB
Certain devices have up to 16 DMA channels and support CTMU. They suit a variety of general-purpose as well as high-end applications.


Microchip Power Management – Battery Management
――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――
Description
Microchip battery charge management controllers.

This collection provides a range of battery charge management controllers, which deliver high accuracy and enable longer battery
operation for portable designs.


Microchip Power Management – Charge Pump
――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――
Description
Microchip charge pump DC-to-DC converters.

This is a collection of inverting, doubling and regulatory converters, up to 120mA.


Microchip Power Management – CPU-System Supervisor
――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――
Description
Microchip CPU/System supervisory circuits.

This is a collection of precision supervisors, with industry-standard functionality and pin-outs.


Microchip Power Management – Hot Swap
――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――
Description
Microchip Hot Swap Controllers.

This is a collection of Hot Swap Controllers, which help prevent damage and operational faults in applications where a line card
needs to be inserted into a live backplane.


Microchip Power Management – Line Regulator
――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――
Description
Microchip linear regulators.

This is a collection of low-power, low-dropout linear regulators.


Microchip Power Management – MOSFET Driver
――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――
Description
Microchip Power MOSFET drivers.

Microchip's Power MOSFET drivers feature wide range input supply voltages and output currents, and offer good latch-up immunity.


Microchip Power Management – PWM Controller
――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――
Description
Microchip PWM Controllers.

Microchip's PWM Controllers are versatile, run at high-speeds (up to 2MHz) and feature microcontroller adaptability.


Microchip Power Management – Switching Regulator
――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――
Description
Microchip Switching Regulators.

This collection provides a range of PFM/PWM Step-down and Step-up DC/DC Controllers and Regulators.


Microchip Power Management – Voltage Detector
――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――
Description
Microchip Voltage Detectors.

This is a collection of space-saving, low-power voltage monitors.


Microchip Power Management – Voltage Reference
――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――
Description
Microchip Voltage References.

This is a collection of low-power, low-dropout precision voltage references, providing precise output voltages of either 2.5V or 4.096V.


Microchip Serial SRAM
――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――
Description
Microchip serial SRAM.

This collection provides Microchip's family of serial SRAM devices. These devices provide a way to add external RAM to almost any
application, while using less power and less connections than traditional parallel SRAM. They are well suited for scratchpad,
buffering and mathematically-intensive applications.
Device features:
  • 8KB (64Kbit) and 32KB (256Kbit) densities available
  • Available in operating voltages of 1.8V or 3V
  • Standard 4-pin SPI interface
  • High-speed SPI bus with maximum operational speed of 16MHz (1.8V versions) or 20MHz (3V versions)
  • low-power operation, typical standby current of 1µA (500nA for 1.8V versions)


Microchip SPI Serial EEPROM
――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――
Description
Microchip SPI serial EEPROM.

This collection provides Microchip's family of SPI serial EEPROM devices. These are high-speed, high-endurance, low-power memory devices,
suited to almost any application.
Device features:
  • 1Kbit to 1Mbit densities available
  • Operating voltage:
      ○ 'AA' devices: 1.8V-5.5V
      ○ 'LC' devices: 2.5V-5.5V
  • Maximum clock frequency of 10MHz (20MHz for 512Kbit and 1Mbit devices)
  • Standard 4-pin SPI interface
  • Whole, half or quarter array write protection
  • High endurance – 1 million erase/write cycles
  • 200 year data retention
  • Wide variety of tiny packages


Microchip Thermal Management
――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――
Description
Microchip temperature sensors, DC fan controllers and fan-fault detectors.

Microchip's temperature sensors are available in three categories – Voltage Output, Logic Output and Serial Output. They are
well-suited to use in thermometer circuits and temperature compensation applications.
Voltage output temperature sensors:
  • Available with typical temperature conversion accuracies of ±0.5°C or ±1°C
  • Operating current as low as 12µA
  • 2.3V to 5.5V available supply voltages
  • -40°C up to +150°C temperature range
  • Available in 6.25mV/°C, 10mV/°C and 19.5mV/°C linear temperature slopes
Logic output temperature sensors:
  • Available with typical temperature threshold accuracies of ±0.5°C or ±1°C
  • Operating current as low as 40µA
  • 2.7V to 18V available supply voltages
  • -40°C to +125°C temperature range (-55°C to +135°C for TC6051/2/3/4 devices)
  • Depending on device, temperature switch thresholds are either factory-programmed, or user-set through an external resistor
  • Programmable hysteresis on certain devices
  • Dual trip-points on certain devices (High and Low temperature point monitoring)
  • External temperature sensor for TC621
Serial output temperature sensors:
  • Available with typical temperature conversion accuracies of ±0.25°C, ±0.5°C or ±2°C
  • Operating current as low as 200µA
  • 2-wire I²C/SMBus-compatible interface or 3/4-wire SPI-compatible interface
  • Standby mode for power savings, (as low as 0.1 µA)
  • High temperature resolution (0.0625°C to 1°C)
  • Fast temperature conversion times
  • Wide temperature range: -55°C to +125°C
Microchip's brushless DC fan controllers use PWM to adjust the speed of a fan in accordance to the temperature level. Many of these
devices require an external thermistor or voltage output temperature sensor to supply the input voltage, while others have integrated
temperature sensors. Certain devices in the range enable fan speed control, and also communication over an SMBus interface, enabling
accurate reading of fan RPM data, and the ability to implement predictive fan-failure detection. Many devices in the range also
provide auto-shutdown and/or over-temperature alert functionality.


Microchip UNIO Serial EEPROM
――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――
Description
Microchip UNI/O serial EEPROM.

This collection provides Microchip's family of UNI/O serial EEPROM devices. The UNI/O serial EEPROM is a single I/O EEPROM device,
developed to work on the UNI/O Bus, a propriety single I/O bus protocol developed by Microchip. The UNI/O Bus combines the clock and
data lines into a single bit stream using the Manchester Encoding technique.
Optimized for embedded applications, a UNI/O serial EEPROM device needs connection to only one pin of an embedded microcontroller,
freeing up pins for other design requirements.
Device features:
  • 1Kbit to 16Kbit densities available
  • Operating voltage:
      ○ 'AA' devices: 1.8V-5.5V
      ○ 'LC' devices: 2.5V-5.5V
  • Frequency range: 10kHz-100kHz
  • Single pin interface
  • Whole, half or quarter array write protection
  • High endurance – 1 million erase/write cycles
  • 200 year data retention
  • Wide variety of tiny packages


Microchip Wireless
――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――
Description
Microchip wireless and KEELOQ devices.
This collection provides a range of wireless devices in the following categories:
  • IEEE 802.15.4/ZigBee RF transceivers – devices operating in the 2.4GHz frequency band. Depending on the device, ZigBee,
    MiWi and MiWi P2P protocols are supported.
  • rfPIC ICs – devices featuring a 20MHz PIC microcontroller and 434MHz ASK/FSK RF transmitter, providing a data rate of 40kbps
  • Standalone UHF ASK/FSK/FM receivers
This collection also provides Microchip's KEELOQ family of secure authentication devices. KEELOQ devices use a non-linear encryption
algorithm that creates a unique transmission on every use, rendering code capture and resend schemes ineffective. KEELOQ authentication
may be applied to many secure applications including:
  • Remote keyless entry systems
  • Gates and garage doors
  • Electronic billing
  • Electronic identification
