Linx Technologies
════════════════════════════════════════════════════════════════

Linx Technologies Antenna
――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――
Description
Linx antennas.

This collection offers a comprehensive selection of antennas in a wide variety of styles and price ranges. Choose from Embeddable
(antennas that attach directly to a PCB inside a case), Magnetic Base (for semi-permanent mounting), high gain, GPS antennas and
many more.


Linx Technologies Connector
――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――
Description
Linx connectors, cable assemblies and accessories.

Linx connectors are designed for RF coaxial applications, with a wide range covering SMA, MCX, MMCX, BNC, TNC, SMB and N connectors,
as well as options for RP (reverse polarity) requirements. Battery holders are also included.


Linx Technologies Integrated Circuit
――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――
Description
Linx ICs.

Linx offers a wide variety of integrated circuits designed to simplify encoding and decoding, interface, and RF implementations with
multi data and address line encoder/decoders, basic remote control (button presses/contact closures), secure encrypted wireless links,
and bidirectional remote controls.


Linx Technologies Interface Module
――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――
Description
Linx interface modules.

Housed in a compact SMD package, the QS-series USB module allows the rapid addition of USB to virtually any device, allowing conversion
between USB and CMOS / TTL logic level serial sources. It is completely self-contained, requires no external components (except a USB
jack), and includes all necessary firmware and drivers.
Power is supplied either externally, or internally from the USB bus. Both USB 1.1 and USB 2.0 are supported at data rates up to 3Mbps.


Linx Technologies RF Module
――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――
Description
Linx RF modules.

Linx RF modules allow engineers of all skill levels to quickly and cost-effectively add wireless capabilities to virtually any product.
Linx hybrid modules are complete RF solutions and require no tuning or external RF components, except an antenna.
