FTDI
════════════════════════════════════════════════════════════════

FTDI Communication
Description
――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――
FTDI USB Interface devices.

This collection consists of the FT-Series family of USB Slave-based converter devices and the Vinculum family of USB Host/Slave
controllers. Together, the designer is afforded total solutions for converting legacy peripherals to the USB connectivity standard.
FTDI devices offer the designer an easy route for the addition of a USB port into their system design or the migration from serial
interfaces, such as RS232 or FIFO, to USB.
The FT-series devices cater for a range of USB Slave Converters. The series includes:
  • FT232H - Single Channel Hi-Speed USB-to-Multipurpose UART/FIFO IC. Operating at USB Hi-Speed (480Mbps), this fast single channel
    bridge chip features either a flexible serial interface or parallel FIFO interface, with data transfer speeds up to 40Mbytes/s.
    Using a serial EEPROM interface, this device can be configured for a wide variety of asynchronous and synchronous serial standards,
    such as JTAG, SPI, I2C and UART as well as synchronous and asynchronous parallel FIFO interfaces. In addition, this device features
    the synchronous, half-duplex FT1248 bus, which allows an engineer to trade off bandwidth for pin count using 1, 2, 4, or 8 data
    lines at up to 30Mbytes/s
  • FT2232H - Hi-Speed USB 2.0 Slave-to-Dual UART/FIFO Converter. Operating at USB Hi-Speed (480Mbps), this device has two independent
    configurable interfaces. Each interface can be configured as UART, FIFO, JTAG, SPI, I2C or bit-bang mode with independent baud rate
    generators. In addition to these, the device supports a host bus emulation mode, a CPU-Style FIFO mode and a fast opto-isolated
    serial interface mode.
  • FT4232H - Hi-Speed USB 2.0 Slave-to-Quad Channel UART/Serial Converter. Operating at USB Hi-Speed (480Mbps), this device features
    4 UARTs. Two of these have an option to independently configure an MPSSE engine, this allows the device to operate as two
    UART/Bit-Bang ports plus two MPSSE engines used to emulate JTAG, SPI, I2C, Bit-bang or other synchronous serial modes.
  • FT2232D - USB 2.0 Slave-to-Dual UART/FIFO Converter. Operating at USB Full Speed (12Mbps), this device has a single downstream USB
    port that is converted to two IO channels which can each be individually configured as a FT232BM-style UART interface, or a
    FT245BM-style FIFO interface, without the need to add a USB hub. In addition a new high drive level option means that the device
    UART/FIFO IO pins will drive out at around three times the normal power level, meaning that the bus can be shared by several
    devices.
  • FT232R - USB 2.0 Slave-to-UART Converter. Operating at USB Full Speed (12Mbps), this device simplifies USB to serial designs and
    reduces external component count by fully integrating an external EEPROM (1024bit), USB termination resistors and an integrated
    clock circuit which requires no external crystal, into the device. Its optional clock output selection enables a glue-less interface
    to an external MCU or FPGA.
  • FT245R - USB 2.0 Slave-to-FIFO Converter. Operating at USB Full Speed (12Mbps), this device simplifies USB to FIFO designs and
    reduces external component count by fully integrating an external EEPROM (1024bit), USB termination resistors and an integrated
    clock circuit which requires no external crystal, into the device.
  • FT232B - USB 2.0 Slave-to-UART Converter. Operating at USB Full Speed (12Mbps), this device simplifies USB to serial designs,
    providing serial data rates of 300-3MBaud (TTL, RS422/RS485) and 300-1MBaud (RS232).
  • FT245B - USB 2.0 Slave-to-FIFO Converter. Operating at USB Full Speed (12Mbps), this device provides an easy cost-effective method
    of transferring data to/from a peripheral and a host P.C. at up to 8 Million bits (1 Megabyte) per second. Its simple,
    FIFO-like design makes it easy to interface to any microcontroller or microprocessor via IO ports.
The Vinculum-II (VNC2) Programmable Dual USB 2.0 Host/Slave controller features a powerful 16-bit MCU core, with embedded 256KB Flash
and 16KB RAM memory. The device supports a range of flexible interfaces including UART, SPI, FIFO and PWM. The complete USB protocol
data processing is handled entirely by hardware resources within the device freeing up processing resources for user developed
applications.
The Vinculum (VNC1L) Embedded USB Host Controller features two independent USB Host/Slave ports with an inbuilt 8/32-bit MCU processing
core with 4KBytes of RAM program memory and 64KBytes of embedded Flash memory for firmware storage. The VNC1L supports UART, SPI slave
and 8-bit parallel FIFO interfaces to enable communication with external processing devices. Further the two USB Ports on the VNC1L can
be individually configured by firmware as Host or Slave ports.


FTDI FT-X Series
――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――
Description
FTDI FT-X Series devices.

This collection consists of the FT-X Series of USB interface devices. The FT-X (X-Chip) series offers full speed USB 2.0 bridging
solutions to UART, SPI/FT1248, I2C and FIFO interfaces. These devices offer lower power, lower pin count, with key features that
include:
  • Battery charger detection to enable higher current, faster charging
  • Extensive clocking capabilities; internal clock generation and external clock out
  • Internal 3.3V regulator
  • Integrated crystal and Multi-Time-Programmable (MTP) memory to save board space and maximize flexibility
