Xilinx
════════════════════════════════════════════════════════════════

Xilinx Aerospace and Defense
――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――
Description
Xilinx Space-Grade and Defense-Grade FPGAs and configuration PROMs.

This collection provides a range of devices suitable for use in aerospace and defense applications. The following Defense-Grade FPGA
families are included here:
  • Virtex-5Q, LX, LXT, SXT and FXT sub-families
  • Virtex-4Q, SX and LX sub-families
  • Virtex-II Pro XQ
  • Virtex-II XQ
  • QPro Virtex-II Pro 1.5V
  • QPro Virtex-II 1.5V Military QML
  • QPro Virtex 2.5V QML
  • QPro Virtex-E 1.8V QML
  • QPro XQ4000E/EX Series
  • QPro XQ4000XL Series
Virtex-5Q FPGAs contain many dedicated system-level blocks, including powerful 36Kbit block RAM/FIFOs, second generation 25 x 18 DSP
slices, SelectIO™ technology with built-in digitally-controlled impedance, ChipSync™ technology source-synchronous interface blocks,
system monitor functionality, enhanced clock management tiles (CMTs) with integrated digital clock managers (DCM) and phaselocked-loop
(PLL) clock generators, and advanced configuration options. Additional device-dependent features include power-optimized, high-speed
serial transceiver blocks for enhanced serial connectivity, PCI Express® compliant integrated Endpoint blocks, tri-mode Ethernet Media
Access Controllers (Ethernet MACs), and high-performance PowerPC® 440 microprocessor embedded blocks. These devices also include
advanced high-speed serial connectivity and link/transaction layer capability.
The Virtex-5Q family offers:
  • Up to 330,000 Logic Cells
  • 500 MHz clocking with clock management tile
  • Up to 6.5Gbps high-performance RocketIO GTX transceivers
  • 528 GMACs from 500 MHz DSP48E slices with 25x18 multipliers for DSP acceleration
  • 192 GFLOPS single-precision and 68 GFLOPS double-precision floating point DSP
The following Space-Grade FPGA families are included in this collection:
  • Virtex-4QV, SX, LX and FX sub-families
  • QPro Virtex-II 1.5V Radiation-Hardened QML
  • QPro Virtex 2.5V Radiation-Hardened
  • QPro XQR4000XL Radiation-Hardened
Virtex-4QV devices offer up to 200,000 logic cells, 10Mbit of RAM/FIFO, two built-in PowerPC® 405 processor blocks with an APU
controller, 512 DSP™ slices, and four built-in Ethernet blocks. These devices deliver outstanding performance with 400Mhz clocking,
DSP slices delivering 204 GMACs at 400MHz, and 350MHz PowerPC processors, all in a single device. Flexible 800 Mbps differential
I/O and 500 Mbps single-ended I/O support industry-standard and custom protocols.
The following configuration PROM devices are included in this collection:
  • QPro XQ18V04 QML In-System Programmable Configuration PROMs
  • QPro XQ17V16 QML Configuration PROMs
  • QPro XQ/XQR1701L QML OTP Configuration PROMs
  • QPro Family of XC1700D QML Configuration PROMs
  • QPro XQR17V16 Radiation Hardened 16Mbit QML Configuration PROM


Xilinx Automotive IQ
――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――
Description
Xilinx Automotive IQ FPGA and CPLD devices.

The Spartan-II 2.5V FPGA Automotive IQ product family gives users high performance, abundant logic resources, and a rich feature set.
The six-member family offers densities ranging from 15,000 to 200,000 system gates.
The Spartan-XL 3.3V FPGA Automotive IQ product family is a high-volume production FPGA solution that delivers all the key requirements
for ASIC replacement up to 40,000 gates.
The CoolRunner XPLA3 (extended Programmable Logic Array) Automotive IQ product family of CPLDs is targeted for low power systems that
include portable, handheld, automotive, and power sensitive applications. Each member of the XPLA3 family includes Fast Zero Power (FZP)
design technology that combines low power and high speed. With this design technique, the XPLA3 family delivers power that is less than
100 μA at standby without the need for "turbo bits" or other power down schemes. The six-member family offers densities ranging from
32 to 512 macrocells (750 to 12,000 usable gates).
The XC9500 CPLD Automotive IQ family provides advanced in-system programming and test capabilities for high performance, general purpose
logic integration. All devices are in-system programmable for a minimum of 10,000 program/erase cycles. Logic density of the XC9500
devices ranges from 800 to 1,600 usable gates with 36 and 72 registers, respectively.
The XC9500XL 3.3V CPLD Automotive IQ product family is targeted for leading-edge, high-performance, low-voltage extended industrial
(–40°C to +125°C) applications.


Xilinx CoolRunner II
――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――
Description
Xilinx CoolRunner-II family of CPLD devices.

CoolRunner-II CPLDs deliver the high speed and ease of use associated with the XC9500/XL/XV CPLD family with the extremely low power
versatility of the XPLA3 family in a single CPLD. Low power consumption and high-speed operation are combined into a single family
that is easy to use and cost effective.


Xilinx CoolRunner XPLA3
――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――
Description
Xilinx CoolRunner XPLA3 family of CPLD devices.

The CoolRunner XPLA3 (eXtended Programmable Logic Array) family of CPLDs is targeted for low power systems that include portable,
handheld, and power sensitive applications. Each member of the XPLA3 family includes Fast Zero Power (FZP) design technology that
combines low power and high speed.


Xilinx Spartan-II
――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――
Description
Xilinx Spartan-II family of FPGA devices.

The Spartan-II family of 2.5V FPGA devices gives users high performance, abundant logic resources, and a rich feature set, all at an
exceptionally low price. The six-member family offers densities ranging from 15,000 to 200,000 system gates. System performance is
supported up to 200MHz.


Xilinx Spartan-IIE
――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――
Description
Xilinx Spartan-IIE family of FPGA devices.

The Spartan-IIE family of 1.8V FPGA devices gives users high performance, abundant logic resources, and a rich feature set, all at
an exceptionally low price. The seven-member family offers densities ranging from 50,000 to 600,000 system gates. System performance
is supported beyond 200MHz.


Xilinx Spartan-3
――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――
Description
Xilinx Spartan-3 family of FPGA devices.

The 1.2V Spartan-3 family of FPGAs is specifically designed to meet the needs of high volume, cost-sensitive consumer electronic
applications. The eight-member family offers densities ranging from 50,000 to 5 million system gates.


Xilinx Spartan-3A
――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――
Description
Xilinx Spartan-3A family of FPGA devices.

The Spartan-3A family of FPGAs solves the design challenges in most high-volume, I/O-intensive electronic applications. Their very low
cost makes them particularly well-suited for use in consumer electronics applications, including home networking and digital television
equipment. The five-member family offers densities ranging from 50,000 to 1.4 million system gates.


Xilinx Spartan-3A DSP
――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――
Description
Xilinx Spartan-3A DSP family of FPGA devices.

The Spartan-3A DSP FPGAs extend and enhance the Spartan-3A FPGA family. Tailored specifically for DSP applications, they possess
additional block RAM and XtremeDSP DSP48A slices. With an impressive DSP price/performance ratio, they are ideally suited for use in
consumer electronics applications. The two-member family offers densities of 1.8 and 3.4 million system gates respectively.


Xilinx Spartan-3AN
――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――
Description
Xilinx Spartan-3AN family of FPGA devices.

The Spartan-3AN family of FPGAs combine the features of the Spartan-3A FPGA device family with In-System Flash memory, for configuration
and non-volatile storage of data. The Spartan-3AN devices are particularly well-suited to applications constrained to limited space,
including GPS, medical devices and other small consumer products. The five-member family offers densities ranging from
50,000 to 1.4 million system gates.


Xilinx Spartan-3E
――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――
Description
Xilinx Spartan-3E family of FPGA devices.

The Spartan-3E family of FPGAs is specifically designed to meet the needs of high volume, cost-sensitive consumer electronic
applications. These devices have enhanced system performance and an increased amount of logic per I/O, in comparison with the
Spartan-3 family of devices. The five-member family offers densities ranging from 100,000 to 1.6 million system gates.


Xilinx Spartan-3L
――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――
Description
Xilinx Spartan-3L family of FPGA devices.

The Spartan-3L family of FPGAs offer a functionally identical, but low-power alternative, to the Spartan-3 family of devices.
The Spartan-3L devices provide static current reduction and also a Hibernate mode – to lower device power consumption.
The three-member family offers densities ranging from 1 to 4 million system gates.


Xilinx Spartan-6
――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――
Description
Xilinx Spartan-6 family of FPGA devices.

Built on a low-power 45nm, 9-metal copper layer, dual-oxide process technology, the sixth generation in the Spartan-series offers
advanced power management technology, integrated PCI Express® blocks, advanced memory support, 250MHz DSP slices and 3.125Gbps
low-power transceivers. The thirteen member family offers densities ranging from 3,840 to 147,443 logic cells.


Xilinx Virtex
――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――
Description
Xilinx Virtex family of FPGA devices.

The Virtex FPGA family delivers high-performance, high-capacity programmable logic solutions. Dramatic increases in silicon
efficiency result from optimizing the new architecture for place-and-route efficiency and exploiting an aggressive 5-layer-metal
0.22µm CMOS process.


Xilinx Virtex-II Pro X
――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――
Description
Xilinx Virtex-II Pro X family of FPGA devices.

The Virtex-II Pro X family contains platform FPGAs for designs that are based on IP cores and customized plugins. The family
incorporates up to 20 RocketIO X embedded Multi-Gigabit Transceivers (MGTs) and up to 2 PowerPC RISC processor blocks. It empowers
complete solutions for telecommunication, wireless, networking, video, and DSP applications.


Xilinx Virtex-4
――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――
Description
Xilinx Virtex-4 family of FPGA devices.

Virtex-4 FPGAs are the first multi-platform FPGA family based on the revolutionary Advanced Silicon Modular Block (ASMBL)
architecture. Between its different platforms (FX, LX and SX), the Virtex-4 family offers a programmable logic solution closely
matching designers needs.


Xilinx Virtex-5
――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――
Description
Xilinx Virtex-5 family of FPGA devices.

Virtex-5 FPGAs are the ultimate system integration platforms utilizing the second generation ASMBL (Advanced Silicon Modular Block)
architecture. Between its different platforms (FXT, LX, LXT, SXT and TXT), the Virtex-5 family offers a programmable logic solution
closely matching designers needs.


Xilinx Virtex-6
――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――
Description
Xilinx Virtex-6 family of FPGA devices.

Virtex-6 FPGAs are the high-performance silicon foundation for Targeted Design Platforms, utilizing the third generation ASMBL
(Advanced Silicon Modular Block) architecture. Consuming 50% lower power and delivering 20% lower cost than the previous generation,
the new family is built with the right mix of programmability, integrated blocks for DSP, memory, and connectivity support. Between
its different platforms (HXT, LXT, and SXT), the Virtex-6 family offers a programmable logic solution closely matching designers needs.


Xilinx XA CoolRunner II
――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――
Description
Xilinx Automotive CoolRunner-II family of CPLD devices.

Xilinx CoolRunner-II Automotive CPLDs deliver the high-speed and ease of use associated with the XA9500XL CPLD family, along with
extremely low-power versatility in a single CPLD. Low power consumption and high-speed operation are combined into a single family
that is easy to use and cost effective.
The five-member family offers densities ranging from 32 to 384 macrocells, between 33 and 118 user I/O and are optimized
for 1.8V systems.


Xilinx XA Spartan-3A
――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――
Description
Xilinx Automotive Spartan-3A family of FPGA devices.

The Xilinx Automotive (XA) Spartan-3A family of FPGAs is ideally suited for use in high-volume, cost-sensitive, I/O-intensive
automotive electronics applications, including infotainment, driver information, and driver assistance plugins. The four-member
family offers densities ranging from 200,000 to 1.4 million system gates, and I/Os ranging from 195 to 375, with support for
industry standard and emerging I/O standards.


Xilinx XA Spartan-3A DSP
――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――
Description
Xilinx Automotive Spartan-3A DSP family of FPGA devices.

The Xilinx Automotive (XA) Spartan-3A DSP family of FPGAs is ideally suited for high-volume, cost-sensitive DSP algorithmic and
co-processing applications in the automotive electronics arena, including infotainment, driver information, and driver assistance
plugins. Significant DSP performance is delivered through embedded MAC blocks. The two-member family offers densities of 1.8 million
and 3.4 million system gates respectively.


Xilinx XA Spartan-3E
――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――
Description
Xilinx Automotive Spartan-3E family of FPGA devices.

The Xilinx Automotive (XA) Spartan-3E family of FPGAs is ideally suited for use in high-volume, cost-sensitive automotive electronics
applications, including infotainment, driver information, and driver assistance plugins. The five-member family offers densities
ranging from 100,000 to 1.6 million system gates, and I/Os ranging from 66 to 376.


Xilinx XA9500XL
――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――
Description
Xilinx Automotive XA9500XL family of CPLD devices.

The Xilinx Automotive (XA) XA9500XL 3.3V CPLD family is targeted for leading-edge, high-performance automotive applications that
require either automotive industrial (–40°C to +85°C ambient) or extended (–40°C to +105°C ambient, with Tj maximum of 125°C)
temperature reconfigurable devices.
This three-member family caters for the following densities:
  • 36 macrocells (800 usable gates)
  • 72 macrocelss (1.600 usable gates)
  • 144 macrocells (3,200 usable gates)
All devices operate with a system frequency up to 64.5Mhz.


Xilinx XCF
――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――
Description
Xilinx XCF family of Platform Flash In-System Programmable Configuration PROM devices.

The XCF Platform Flash family of in-system programmable configuration PROMs provide an easy-to-use, cost-effective method for
reprogramming and storing large Xilinx FPGA configuration bitstreams. The family includes 3.3V XCFxxS (4Mb, 2Mb, 1Mb) and 1.8V XCFxxP
(32Mb, 16Mb, 16Mb) flavors of PROM device.


Xilinx XC17S00
――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――
Description
Xilinx XC17S00/XL family of OTP Configuration PROM devices.

The XC17S00 (5V) and XC17S00XL (3.3V) families of configuration PROMs provide an easy-to-use, cost-effective method for storing
Spartan/Spartan-XL device configuration bitstreams. These devices are one-time programmable (OTP) read-only memory.
The five-member XC17S00 family caters for densities ranging from 53,984 configuration bits, up to 329,312 configuration bits.
The eight-member XC17S00XL family caters for densities ranging from 54.544 configuration bits, up to 1,040,096 configuration bits.


Xilinx XC17S00A
――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――
Description
Xilinx XC17S00A family of OTP Configuration PROM devices.

The XC17S00A family of 3.3V PROMs provide an easy-to-use, cost-effective method for storing SpartanII/Spartan-IIE device configuration
bitstreams. These devices are one-time programmable (OTP) read-only memory.
The 11-member family cater for densities ranging from 197,696 configuration bits up to 1,875,648 configuration bits.


Xilinx XC17V00
――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――
Description
Xilinx XC17V00 family of Configuration PROM devices.

The XC17V00 3.3V family of configuration PROMs provide an easy-to-use, cost-effective method for storing large Xilinx FPGA configuration
bitstreams. These devices are one-time programmable (OTP) read-only memory. The five-member family caters for 1Mb, 2Mb, 4Mb, 8Mb,
and 16Mb densities.
The 8Mb and 16Mb devices provide dual-configuration modes:
  • Serial slow/fast configuration (up to 20Mbps)
  • Parallel (up to 160Mbps at 20MHz)


Xilinx XC18V00
――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――
Description
Xilinx XC18V00 family of In-System Programmable Configuration PROM devices.

The XC18V00 3.3V family of in-system programmable configuration PROMs include a 4-megabit, a 2-megabit, a 1-megabit, and a 512-kilobit
PROM that provide an easy-to-use, cost-effective method for re-programming and storing Xilinx FPGA configuration bitstreams.


Xilinx XC1700
――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――
Description
Xilinx XC1700L family of OTP Configuration PROM devices.

The XC1700L (3.3V) family of configuration PROMs provides an easy-to-use, cost-effective method for storing large Xilinx FPGA
configuration bitstreams. Devices can be cascaded to enable storage of longer, or multiple bitstreams. These devices are one-time
programmable (OTP) read-only memory.
The four-member family caters for 512Kbit, 1Mbit, 2Mbit and 4Mbit densities.


Xilinx XC1700E
――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――
Description
Xilinx XC1700E and XC1700EL family of OTP Configuration PROM devices.

The XC1700E (5V) and XC1700EL (3.3V) families of configuration PROMs provide an easy-to-use, cost-effective method for storing
large Xilinx FPGA configuration bitstreams. Devices can be cascaded to enable storage of longer, or multiple bitstreams. These
devices are one-time programmable (OTP) read-only memory.
The four-member XC1700E family caters for 36Kbit, 64Kbit, 128Kbit and 256Kbit densities.
The three-member XC1700EL family caters for 64Kbit, 128Kbit and 256Kbit densities.


Xilinx XC5200
――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――
Description
Xilinx XC5200 family of FPGA devices.

The XC5200 family brings a robust feature set to programmable logic design. The VersaBlock logic module, the VersaRing I/O interface,
and a rich hierarchy of interconnect resources combine to enhance design flexibility and reduce time-to-market.
The five-member family feature:
  • 256 to 1,936 logic cells (3000 to 23,000 max logic gates)
  • System performance beyond 50MHz
  • 64 to 484 CLBs
  • 84 to 244 I/Os


Xilinx XC9500
――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――
Description
Xilinx XC9500 family of In-System Programmable CPLD devices.

The XC9500 CPLD family provides advanced in-system programming and test capabilities for high performance, general purpose logic
integration. All devices are in-system programmable for a minimum of 10,000 program/erase cycles.


Xilinx XC9500XL
――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――
Description
Xilinx XC9500XL family of High Performance CPLD devices.

The FastFLASH XC9500XL family is a 3.3V CPLD family targeted for high-performance, low-voltage applications in leading edge
communications and computing systems, where high device reliability and low power dissipation is important.


Xilinx XC9500XV
――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――
Description
Xilinx XC9500XV family of High Performance CPLD devices.

The XC9500XV family is a 2.5V CPLD family targeted for high-performance, low-voltage applications in leading edge communications
and computing systems, where high device reliability and low power dissipation is important.
