Actel Libraries
════════════════════════════════════════════════════════════════


Actel Axcelerator
――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――
Description
Actel Axcelerator family of antifuse FPGA devices.

The Actel Axcelerator family of devices offer a high-performance, single-chip, non-volatile solution, with densities ranging
from 125,000 to 2 million equivalent system gates and up to 684 I/Os. Using the Actel AX architecture, these devices incorporate
several system-level features, including up to 295kbits of embedded SRAM (with programmable embedded FIFO control logic),
8 PLLs (with output up to 1GHz), segmentable clocks, and up to 10,752 dedicated register (flip-flop) cells.
Each device is manufactured using advanced 0.15µm CMOS Antifuse process technology, and incorporates FuseLock programming
technology – protecting against reverse engineering and the possibility of design theft.


Actel eX
――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――
Description
Actel Ex family of antifuse FPGA devices.

The Actel Ex family of devices offer a high-performance, low-power, single-chip, non-volatile solution, with densities ranging
from 3000 to 12,000 system gates and up to 132 user-programmable I/Os. These devices are well suited to power-sensitive applications.
Each device is manufactured using advanced 0.22µm CMOS Antifuse process technology, and incorporates FuseLock programming
technology – protecting against reverse engineering and the possibility of design theft.


Actel Fusion
――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――
Description
Actel Fusion family of mixed-signal Flash FPGA devices.

The Actel Fusion Programmable System Chip (PSC) is a mixed-signal FPGA, integrating configurable analog, large Flash memory blocks,
comprehensive clock generation and management circuitry, and high performance programmable logic in a monolithic device to provide
the ideal platform for high performance applications.


Actel IGLOO
――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――
Description
Actel IGLOO family of low-power Flash FPGA devices.

The IGLOO family of Flash FPGAs is designed to meet the requirements of today's portable electronics. With the Cortex-M1 soft core,
M1 IGLOO devices offer the benefits of programmability. The IGLOO family is based on nonvolatile Flash technology and support between
15,000 to 3 million gates and up to 620 high performance I/Os.


Actel IGLOOe
――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――
Description
Actel IGLOOe family of low-power Flash FPGA devices.

The IGLOOe family of Flash FPGAs is designed to meet the requirements of today's portable electronics. With the Cortex-M1 soft core,
M1 IGLOOe devices offer the benefits of programmability. The IGLOOe family is based on nonvolatile Flash technology and support up to
3 million gates and up to 620 high performance I/Os.


Actel IGLOO nano
――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――
Description
Actel IGLOO nano family of low-power Flash FPGA devices.

The IGLOO nano family of Flash FPGAs offer groundbreaking possibilities in power, size and operating temperature. The IGLOO nano family
is based on nonvolatile Flash technology and support between 10,000 to 250,000 gates and up to 77 high performance I/Os in small
footprint packages between 3x3mm to 14x17mm.


Actel IGLOO PLUS
――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――
Description
Actel IGLOO PLUS family of low-power Flash FPGA devices.

The IGLOO PLUS family of Flash FPGAs is designed to meet the requirements of today's portable electronics. The IGLOO PLUS family
is based on nonvolatile Flash technology and support from 30,000 to 125,000 gates and up to 212 high performance I/Os supporting
independent Schmitt trigger inputs and hot-swapping.


Actel MX
――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――
Description
Actel MX family of antifuse FPGA devices.

The Actel 40MX and 42MX device families offer a high-performance, low-power, single-chip solution with a flexible 5V architecture.
They are well-suited to the integration and consolidation of logic implemented in multiple CPLDs, PALs and FPGAs.
Densities range from 3000 to 54,000 system gates, and up to 202 user-programmable I/Os.
42MX24 and 42MX36 devices also provide selectable PCI-compliant output drives. In addition, the 42MX36 device also offers
ten 256-bit dual-port SRAM modules, which can be arranged in 64x4 or 32x8 configurations.
Each device is manufactured using advanced 0.45µm CMOS Antifuse process technology, and incorporates FuseLock programming
technology – protecting against reverse engineering and the possibility of design theft.


Actel ProASIC PLUS
――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――
Description
Actel ProASICPLUS family of low-power Flash FPGA devices.

The ProASICPLUS family of devices, Actel’s second generation Flash FPGAs, offers enhanced performance over Actel’s ProASIC family.
It combines the advantages of ASICs with the benefits of programmable devices through nonvolatile Flash technology. This enables
engineers to create high density systems using existing ASIC or FPGA design flows and tools. In addition, the ProASICPLUS family
offers a unique clock conditioning circuit based on two on-board phase-locked loops (PLLs). The family offers up to 1 million system
gates, supported with up to 198Kbits of dual-port SRAM and up to 712 user I/Os, all providing 50 MHz PCI performance.


Actel ProASIC3
――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――
Description
Actel ProASIC3 family of low-power Flash FPGA devices.

The ProASIC3 family of Flash FPGAs offer a breakthrough in price, performance, density, and features for today's most demanding
applications. With the Cortex-M1 (ARM) and CoreMP7 (ARM7) soft processor IP cores, M1 and M7 ProASIC3 devices offer the benefits
of programmability and time-to-market at an ASIC-level unit cost. The ProASIC3 family is based on nonvolatile Flash technology and
supports between 15,000 to 1 million gates and up to 300 high performance I/Os.


Actel ProASIC3E
――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――
Description
Actel ProASIC3E family of low-power Flash FPGA devices.

The ProASIC3E family of Flash FPGAs offer a breakthrough in price, performance, density, and features for today's most demanding
applications. With the Cortex-M1 (ARM) and CoreMP7 (ARM7) soft processor IP cores, M1 and M7 ProASIC3E devices offer the benefits
of programmability and time-to-market at an ASIC-level unit cost. The ProASIC3E family is based on nonvolatile Flash technology
and support between 600,000 to 3 million gates and up to 620 high performance I/Os.


Actel ProASIC3L
――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――
Description
Actel ProASIC3L family of low-power Flash FPGA devices.

ProASIC3L FPGAs offer low-power and high-performance in a true single-chip solution, that is live at power-up (LAPU). Using Actel's
proven Flash*Freeze technology enables users to shut off dynamic power instantaneously and switch the device to static mode without
the need to switch off clocks or power supplies while retaining internal states of the device.
A ProASIC3L device can operate from a single voltage (ranging from 1.2 V to 1.5 V core supply), and deliver high operating speed
(250MHz for 1.2V systems and 350MHz for 1.5V systems). These devices offer 1Kbit of on-chip, reprogrammable, nonvolatile FlashROM
storage as well as clock conditioning circuitry (CCC) based on an integrated phase-locked loop (PLL). Devices in the family offer
from 250,000 to 3 million system gates with up to 504 Kbits of true dual-port SRAM and up to 620 user I/Os.
M1 ProASIC3L devices support the high-performance, 32-bit Cortex-M1 processor developed by ARM for implementation in FPGAs.
ARM Cortex-M1 is a soft processor that is fully implemented in the FPGA fabric. It has a three-stage pipeline that offers a good
balance between low-power consumption and speed when implemented in an M1 ProASIC3L device. The processor runs the ARMv6-M instruction set,
has a configurable nested interrupt controller, and can be implemented with or without the debug block.



Actel ProASIC3 nano
――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――
Description
Actel ProASIC3 nano family of low-power Flash FPGA devices.

ProASIC3 nano low-cost, low-power FPGAs are specifically optimized for consumer, industrial, medical, and other high-volume,
cost-sensitive applications. Enhanced I/O functionality ensures multiple standards with mixed voltage levels typically found in power
sensitive or battery powered designs can be addressed with a single device. ProASIC3 nano devices support Schmitt trigger inputs and
are hot-swappable. The Schmitt trigger input delivers greater noise immunity in the circuit, enabling designers to safely identify an
input signal that rises slowly, such as a keyboard or touchpad. The hot-swap capability offers designers the flexibility to maintain direct
system connection while powering up.
ProASIC3 nano devices offer:
  • 10,000 to 250,000 system gates
  • 1Kbit of on-chip, reprogrammable, nonvolatile FlashROM storage
  • Up to 36Kbits of True Dual-Port SRAM (A3PN060 or larger devices)
  • 350MHz system performance
  • Clock conditioning circuitry based on an integrated phase-locked loop (PLL) (A3PN060 or larger devices)
  • Up to 77 user I/Os
ProASIC3 nano devices are available in two feature grades – 'Standard" and "Z". For the A3PN060, A3PN125, and A3PN250, the Z feature grade
does not support the enhanced nano features of Schmitt trigger input, cold-sparing, and hot-swap I/O capability. The A3PN030 Z feature grade
does not support Schmitt trigger input.


Actel RTAX
――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――
Description
Actel RTAX-S/SL and RTAX-DSP families of radiation-tolerant FPGA devices.

RTAX-S/SL offers high performance at densities of up to 4 million equivalent system gates and 840 user I/Os for space-based applications.
Based on the Axcelerator family of devices, the RTAX-S/SL family features SEU-hardened flip-flops implemented without any user intervention,
and offers the benefits of user-implemented triple module redundancy (TMR) without the associated overhead.
RTAX-S/SL family features:
  • Available in densities ranging from 250,000 to 4 million system gates
  • Up to 20,160 SEU-hardened flip-flops
  • Up to 540Kbits of embedded memory with optional EDAC protection
  • 350+MHz system performance (500+MHz internal performance)
  • Up to 840 User I/Os
  • 1.5 V, 1.8 V, 2.5 V, 3.3 V Mixed Voltage Operation
  • SEU immune to LETTH > 37 MeV-cm2/mg
  • SEU less than 1E-10 errors per bit-day (worst-case geosynchronous orbit)
  • SEL immune to LETTH in excess of 117 MeV-cm2/mg
  • Total Dose: 300krad (functional) and 200krad (parametric)
RTAX-DSP space-flight FPGAs add embedded radiation-tolerant multiply-accumulate blocks to the RTAX-S product family. The result is a dramatic
increase in device performance and utilization when implementing arithmetic functions, such as those encountered in DSP algorithms, without
sacrificing reliability or radiation tolerance. RTAX-DSP integrates complex DSP functions into a single device without any external components
for code storage and without multiple-chip implementations for radiation mitigation. This gives RTAX-DSP a significant advantage in power
consumption and heat dissipation relative to SRAM-based FPGAs.
RTAX-DSP offers high performance at densities of up to 4 million equivalent system gates and 840 user I/Os for space-based applications.
Embedded radiation-tolerant DSP mathblocks feature 18 bit x 18 bit multiply-accumulate blocks enabling efficient implementation of DSP building
blocks such as finite impulse response (FIR) and infinite impulse response (IIR) digital filters, fast Fourier transforms (FFT) and inverse
Fourier transforms (IFT), discrete cosine transforms (DCT), and Reed Solomon encoding algorithms. The RTAX-DSP family features up to
120 mathblocks, each capable of operating at 125 MHz over the full military temperature range (-55°C to 125°C), for a total throughput
of 15 billion multiply/accumulates per second (15 GMACS).
RTAX-DSP family features:
  • Available in two densities, offering 2 million or 4 million system gates
  • Up to 18,480 SEU-hardened flip-flops
  • Up to 540Kbits of embedded memory with optional EDAC protection
  • 350+MHz system performance (500+MHz internal performance)
  • Up to 840 User I/Os
  • Up to 120 DSP mathblocks with 125 MHz 18 bit x 18 bit multiply-accumulate
  • 1.5 V, 1.8 V, 2.5 V, 3.3 V Mixed Voltage Operation
  • SEU immune to LETTH > 37 MeV-cm2/mg
  • SEU less than 1E-10 errors per bit-day (worst-case geosynchronous orbit)
  • SEL immune to LETTH in excess of 117 MeV-cm2/mg
  • Total Dose: 300krad (functional) and 200krad (parametric)


Actel RT ProASIC3
――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――
Description
Actel RT ProASIC3 family of radiation-tolerant FPGA devices.

RT ProASIC3 FPGAs offer designers of space-flight hardware a Radiation-Tolerant (RT), reprogrammable, nonvolatile logic integration vehicle.
They are intended for low-power space applications requiring up to 350MHz operation and up to 3 million system gates.
Devices in the RT ProASIC3 family use flash cells to store configuration information. Positive or negative charge stored on floating-gate
transistors is used to hold pass transistors in either the "on" or "off" states, thereby opening or closing connections between routing tracks
and logic resources. This use of flash-based interconnects present some unique opportunities and advantages to designers of space-flight
electronic hardware:
  • The flash cells are reprogrammable – allowing the design of the FPGA to be changed without removing the FPGA from the board, and also
    allowing for the possibility of in-flight reprogrammability, so that mission life can be extended by re-purposing the hardware to
    incorporate updated algorithms.
  • The flash cells are nonvolatile – flash-based FPGAs are standalone devices which do not require the provision of external code-storage
    devices, unlike SRAM-based FPGAs. This minimizes the board space used, and has an associated saving in mass.
  • RT ProASIC3 FPGAs are operating almost at the instant of power-up – another advantage of the nonvolatility of the flash programming
    cells. There is no boot sequence required, as in SRAM-based FPGAs which need to download their configuration code from an external
    storage device.
  • The flash cells do not exhibit single-event upsets in the presence of heavy ion radiation – no triple-chip redundancy to mitigate
    configuration upsets is required, unlike SRAM FPGAs.
Family features:
  • Available in two densities, 600,000 or 3 million system gates
  • Up to 504Kbits of True Duual-Port SRAM
  • 1Kbit of on-chip, reprogrammable, nonvolatile FlashROM storage
  • Up to 620 User I/Os


Actel RTSX-SU
――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――
Description
Actel RTSX-SU family of radiation-tolerant FPGA devices.

RTSX-SU RadTolerant FPGAs are enhanced versions of Actel’s SX-A family of devices, specifically designed for enhanced radiation
performance. Featuring SEU-hardened D-type flip-flops that offer the benefits of Triple Module Redundancy (TMR) without the
associated overhead, wider clock lines and stronger clock drivers, the RTSX-SU family is well-suited to space applications.
They offer Single-Event Latch-Up (SEL) immunity, and can withstand up to 100krad (Si) Total Ionizing Dose (TID).
Family features:
  • Available in two densities, 48,000 or 108,000 system gates
  • Up to 2,012 SEU-hardened flip-flops
  • 230MHz system performance (310MHz internal performance)
  • Up to 360 User I/Os
  • Configurable I/O support for 3.3 V/5 V PCI, LVTTL, TTL, and CMOS
  • Immune to Single-Event Upsets (SEU) to LETTH > 40 MeV-cm2/mg
  • SEU Rate < E10–10 upset/bit-day in worst-case geosynchronous orbit
  • Hermetically-sealed packages for space applications (CQFP, CCGA/LGA, CCLG)


Actel SmartFusion
――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――
Description
Actel SmartFusion family of mixed-signal Flash FPGA devices.

The Actel SmartFusion intelligent mixed-signal FPGAs are devices that integrate an FPGA, ARM Cortex-M3, and programmable analog,
offering full customization, IP protection, and ease-of-use. SmartFusion FPGAs are ideal for hardware and embedded designers who
need a true system-on-chip (SoC) solution.


Actel SX-A
――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――
Description
Actel SX-A family of antifuse FPGA devices.

The Actel SX-A family of FPGAs offers a cost-effective, single-chip solution for low-power, high-performance designs. Fabricated
on 0.22 μm / 0.25 μm CMOS antifuse technology and with the support of 2.5 V, 3.3 V and 5 V I/Os, the SX-A is a versatile platform
to integrate designs while significantly reducing time to market.
The SX-A family architecture is described as a “sea-of-modules” architecture because the entire floor of the device is covered with
a grid of logic modules with virtually no chip area lost to interconnect elements or routing.
Family features:
  • Available in densities ranging from 12,000 to 108,000 system gates
  • Up to 2,012 dedicated flip-flops
  • 250MHz system performance (350MHz internal performance)
  • Up to 360 User I/Os
  • 66 MHz, 64-bit 3.3 V / 5.0 V PCI performance (supporting Target, Master and Master/Target)
  • 2.5 V, 3.3 V, and 5.0 V mixed-voltage support
