Altera Libraries
════════════════════════════════════════════════════════════════


Altera Arria GX
――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――
Description
Altera Arria GX family of FPGA devices.

The Arria GX FPGA family is based on 90-nm and combines low power with high performance and density. This Protocol-Optimized
FPGA makes Arria GX devices ideal for PCI Express (x1, x4). Gigabit Ethernet and Serial RapidIO applications.


Altera Arria II GX
――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――
Description
Altera Arria II GX family of FPGA devices.

Arria II GX FPGAs provide high functionality for 6G transceiver-based applications. Based on a 40-nm process, these devices offer:
  • Device densities up to 256,500 equivalent logic elements (LEs).
  • up to sixteen 6.375Gbps transceivers
  • LVDS at 1.25Gbps
  • Support for 400MHz DD3


Altera Cyclone
――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――
Description
Altera Cyclone family of FPGA devices.

The Cyclone field programmable gate array family is based on a 1.5V, 0.13µm, all-layer copper SRAM process, with densities up to 20,060
logic elements (LEs) and up to 288Kbits of RAM.


Altera Cyclone II
――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――
Description
Altera Cyclone II family of FPGA devices.

Cyclone II devices offer a good solution for cost-sensitive applications, due to its low cost LE. It can contain up to 68K of LE,
and up to 1Mbits of RAM. Supporting single-ended and differential IO signaling standards as well as the Nios2 processors.


Altera Cyclone III
――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――
Description
Altera Cyclone III family of FPGA devices.

Cyclone III devices offer a good solution for cost-sensitive applications due to its low cost LE. They include a wide range of density,
memory, embedded multiplier and packaging options and provide support for single-ended and differential IO signalling standards as well
as the Nios II processors.


Altera Cyclone IV E
――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――
Description
Altera Cyclone IV E family of FPGA devices.

The Cyclone IV E family of devices extends the Cyclone FPGA series in providing low cost, low power FPGAs. They include a wide range
of density, memory, embedded multiplier and packaging options and provide support for single-ended and differential IO signaling
standards as well as the Nios II processors.


Altera Cyclone IV GX
――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――
Description
Altera Cyclone IV GX family of FPGA devices.

The Cyclone IV GX family of devices extends the Cyclone FPGA series in providing low cost, low power FPGAs with transceivers.
They include a wide range of density, memory, embedded multiplier and packaging options and provide up to eight integrated 3.125Gbps
transceivers, as well as the Nios II processors.


Altera EPC
――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――
Description
Altera EPC family of enhanced configuration devices.

The 3.3V EPC family provide a single-device, high-speed, advanced configuration solution for very high-density FPGAs. The core of an
ECP device is divided into two major blocks: a configuration controller and a Flash memory. The Flash memory is used to store
configuration data for systems made up of one or more Altera FPGAs. Unused portions of the Flash memory can be used to store processor
code or data that can be accessed via the external Flash interface after FPGA configuration is complete.
EPC devices are offered in memory densities of 4Mbits, 8Mbits and 16Mbits, making it easy to match the optimal solution to a device's
configuration needs.


Altera EPCS
――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――
Description
Altera EPCS family of serial configuration devices.

The 3.3V EPCS family are designed for maximum efficiency and offer in-system programmability (ISP) and reprogramming capabilities
that are not available with one-time-programmable devices. They are the ideal complement to Cyclone and Arria series FPGAs.
They also provide a low-cost, small-form-factor solution for Stratix series FPGAs.
EPCS devices are offered in memory densities ranging from 1Mbits to 256Mbits, making it easy to match the optimal solution to a
device's configuration needs.


Altera MAX II
――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――
Description
Altera MAX II family of CPLD devices.

MAX II devices are low-cost CPLDs containing low-power process technology, delivering twice the performance of previous MAX devices.
With an on-chip regulator accepting 1.8-3.3V of power supply, it can support clock frequencies of up to 300MHz.


Altera MAX V
――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――
Description
Altera MAX V family of CPLD devices.

MAX V devices are ideal for general-purpose and power- and space-constrained designs in many market segments, including wireline,
wireless, industrial, consumer, computer and storage, broadcast, and military. They are particularly well-suited to applications
such as:
  • I/O expansion
  • Bus and protocol bridging
  • Power monitoring and control
  • FPGA configuration
  • Analog IC interface
Device features:
  • Up to 2,210 logic elements (LEs)
  • Up to 1,700 equivalent macrocells
  • 8Kbits user Flash memory
  • 4 global clocks and control pins
  • 1 internal oscillator
  • Digital PLL
  • Up to 271 maximum user I/O pins


Altera Stratix II
――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――
Description
Altera Stratix II family of FPGA devices.

The Stratix II FPGA family is based on a 1.2-V, 90-nm, all-layer copper SRAM process and features a logic structure that maximizes
performance, and enables device densities approaching 180,000 equivalent logic elements (LEs).


Altera Stratix II GX
――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――
Description
Altera Stratix II GX family of FPGA devices.

The Stratix II GX FPGA technology is built on the Stratix II architecture and offers a 1.2-V logic array with unmatched performance,
flexibility and time-to-market capabilities. This scalable, high-performance architecture makes Stratix II GX devices ideal for
high-speed backplane interface, chip-to-chip and communications protocol-bridging applications.


Altera Stratix III
――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――
Description
Altera Stratix III family of FPGA devices.

The Stratix III FPGA family is based on 65-nm and combines lower power with higher performance and density. This scalable,
high-performance architecture makes Stratix III devices ideal for next-generation base stations, network infrastructure and
advanced imaging equipment.


Altera Stratix IV E/GT/GX
――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――
Description
Altera Stratix IV E family of FPGA devices.
―――――――――――――――――――
Stratix IV FPGAs deliver a breakthrough level of system bandwidth and power efficiency for high-end applications, and are based
on 40-nm process technology.
Stratix IV E (enhanced) FPGAs offer up to 820K logic elements (LEs), 23.1MB RAM, and up to 1,288 18x18 multipliers.

Description
Altera Stratix IV GT family of FPGA devices.
――――――――――――――――――――
Stratix IV GT FPGAs with embedded transceivers deliver breakthrough levels of system bandwidth and power efficiency for
high-end applications. The transceivers are based on 40-nm technology and include a number of features that ensure excellent jitter
performance combined with superior signal integrity for both backplane and chip-to-chip applications.
These FPGAs offer up to 530K logic elements (LEs) and 48 full-duplex clock data recovery (CDR)-based transceivers at up to 11.3Gbps.

Description
Altera Stratix IV GX family of FPGA devices.
――――――――――――――――――――
Stratix IV GT FPGAs with embedded transceivers deliver breakthrough levels of system bandwidth and power efficiency for high-end
applications. The transceivers are based on 40-nm technology and include a number of features that ensure excellent jitter
performance combined with superior signal integrity for both backplane and chip-to-chip applications. The Stratix IV GX FPGA is
fully PCI-SIG compliant for PCI Express Gen1 and Gen2 (x1, x4, and x8).
Stratix IV GX FPGAs offer up to 530K logic elements (LEs) and 48 full-duplex clock data recovery (CDR)-based transceivers
at up to 8.5Gbps.
