Wuerth (Würth) Eleltronik
════════════════════════════════════════════════════════════════

Wuerth Elektronik Common Mode Line Filter
――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――
Description
Wuerth Elektronik Common Mode Line Filters.

Common mode line filters include the WE-CNSW series in 0603-1206 packages, the WE-SLx series and WE-SLM series. The WE-CNSW series is
the only line filter in the product portfolio which is not based on a ring core, but this is the only way to realize such a tight
component. However, the stray field is negligible because the component is a closed system made of ferrite.
The WE-SLx series is built with rectangle or toroidal cores, that almost completely eliminates stray fields. The variety of forms and
the small height provides solutions for a wide range of applications.
The line filter WE-SLM comes with a small base area and high common-mode impedance. The NiZn ferrite is used to provide a wide range
operating temperature. At the same time, the stray inductance is smaller with less influence on the wanted signal. This makes this series
appropriate for higher signal frequencies.


Wuerth Elektronik Common Mode Power Line Choke
――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――
Description
Wuerth Elektronik Common Mode Power Line Chokes.

Common mode power line chokes cover the WE-LF series, with the choke lying in a housing, available in horizontal and vertical design,
as well as the WE-LF SMD series, designed for SMD mounting. The WE-FC and the WE-CMB series are power line chokes without housing.
The special design of the common mode choke WE-CMB allows a reduction of unwanted parasitic effects. The nearly ideal core/winding
ratio allows very high current strengths compared to the area.
The WE-CMB HC series is optimized for higher currents. A 10A rated current can be realized on a quite small component. A peculiarity
in the WE-CMB series is the NiZn variant using NiZn as the base material. This makes it possible to suppress asymmetrical interferences
up to high-frequencies.
The stray inductance of the WE-FC series is doubled to comparable toroidal chokes. The effect on symmetric interference increases,
without the need of an additional inductance. By building a multi-chamber coil bobbin, the parasitic shunt capacitance is reduced.
The impedance curve is increased at high frequencies.


Wuerth Elektronik Double Choke
――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――
Description
Wuerth Elektronik Double Chokes.

The magnetically shielded WE-DD series of double chokes, in contrast to the single-wound inductors, have two identical, separate
windings on a common ferrite core. The application spectrum of this reactor is large, it can be used in 1:1-flyback applications,
buck, boost, SEPIC and CUK switching regulators and switching regulators with a second, unregulated output voltage. When using them
in series and parallel arrangements, even more choke solutions become available.


Wuerth Elektronik EMC Ferrite
――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――
Description
Wuerth Elektronik EMC Ferrites.

This collection provides SMD ferrites, SMD ferrites for HF applications, VHF chokes, a kind of ‘choke array’ with a ferrite bridge
and flat wire high current SMD ferrites as well as SMD power ferrites.


Wuerth Elektronik Filter Inductor
――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――
Description
Wuerth Elektronik Filter Inductors.

This collection provides SMD multilayer inductors (0603-1206) and rod core chokes. With their compact design, multi-layer inductors
achieve a small DC resistance. The external ferrite casing provides a magnetic shield, signal interference and crosstalk is reduced
significantly. The device is particularly suited in filters and resonant circuits, where low coupling and small packages are required.
The rod core choke is not shielded and available in larger packages. The advantage of this design is the broad attenuation and the
current capacity, up to 15A.


Wuerth Elektronik SMD High Current Choke
――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――
Description
Wuerth Elektronik SMD High Current Chokes.

This collection provides a range of SMD High Current Chokes across four series:
  • WE-HCI
  • WE-HCC
  • WE-HCF
  • WE-HCM
The WE-HCx series offers robust, smoothing chokes with a high modulation range - especially suited to use in high current regulators
and multi-phase (or poly-phase) converters. Also used in applications for high current radio-interference suppression chokes.
These high current chokes also have low losses in the core and very high saturation currents. The flat wire coils used in the HCI,
HCF and HCM series also reduce the skin effect and copper losses.


Wuerth Elektronik SMD Power Choke
――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――
Description
Wuerth Elektronik SMD Power Chokes.

The SMD power chokes of Wuerth are divided between magnetically shielded and unshielded inductors. The magnetically shielded inductors
are represented by the families WE-PD, WE-PD3, WE-PDF, WE-TPC, and the power multilayer inductors WE-PMI. The families WE-PD2, WE-PD4,
WE-GF and WE-LQ are magnetically unshielded.
The inductors are optimized for use in switching regulators and DC-DC converters, optimized in the selection of the core and winding
design. Furthermore, these components realize a stable inductance over a wide range of frequencies. In the area of switching regulator
applications, the choke is used for intermediate storage of electrical energy and also for smoothing the output current.
Nickel-Tin alloy used for the core results in very low losses and high modulations. This makes them particularly suitable for use
in switching regulator applications up to 10 MHz while they offer a high current capacity and low DC resistance in a very small package.
The miniature power chokes WE-TPC are suitable for applications where a high package density and a low height are required.


Wuerth Elektronik THT Power Choke
――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――
Description
Wuerth Elektronik THT Power Chokes.

The THT Power Chokes are separated in magnetically shielded and unshielded inductors. The barrel inductor WE-TI is available in both
variations and is available with shrink tubes as well. This serves as a winding protection against external mechanical influences.
These inductors, and their core and coil parameters, are optimized for use in switching regulators and DC-DC converters. The WE-TI
components deliver stable inductance values over a large bandwidth and are particularly suitable for use in switching regulator
applications up to 10 MHz as they offer a high current capacity and low DC resistance in a very small package.
