Freescale Semiconductor
════════════════════════════════════════════════════════════════

Freescale Semiconductor ColdFire MCU
――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――
Description
Freescale ColdFire V1 and V2 32-bit microcontrollers.

ColdFire V1 microcontrollers have 8/32-bit compatible architecture, with a standardized 8-bit bus to S08 peripherals and tightly-coupled
32-bit local memories (Flash and SRAM), providing access to 32-bit performance.
ColdFire V2 microcontrollers are cost effective, 32-bit embedded controllers, combining high performance and extended functionality
with flexibility or advanced Flash memory technology in a compact, inexpensive package.


Freescale Semiconductor ColdFire MPU
――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――
Description
Freescale ColdFire V2 and V3 microprocessors.

ColdFire V2 microprocessors deliver up to 159MIPS at 166MHz, and feature Ethernet, USB and Encryption.
ColdFire V3 microprocessors deliver up to 211MIPS at 240MHz, and feature Ethernet, a USB host, USB with OTG connectivity, and Encryption.


Freescale Semiconductor DSC
――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――
Description
Freescale Digital Signal Controllers.

Digital Signal Controllers offer optimized solutions for Digital Power Conversion, Motor Control and many other applications requiring
high-speed, high-resolution control loop capability. They combine the processing power of a digital signal processor (DSP) and
the functionality of a microcontroller (MCU) with a flexible set of peripherals, producing a cost-effective solution.


Freescale Semiconductor Kinetis ARM
――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――
Description
Freescale Kinetis ARM microcontrollers.

Kinetis ARM Cortex-M4 devices are 32-bit microcontrollers including such features as:
  • A Floating Point Unit
  • USB
  • Segmented LCD
  • Ethernet
  • Integrated Measurement Engine
  • Encryption
  • Tamper Detection
