National Semiconductor
════════════════════════════════════════════════════════════════

National Semiconductor ADC
――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――
Description
National Semiconductor Analog to Digital Converters.

This collection provides Analog to Digital Converters ranging from 1 to 8 channels, 8- to 16-bit, with low power options.


National Semiconductor Amplifier
――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――
Description
National Semiconductor Amplifiers.

This collection offers amplifiers from single to quad, up to 1.7GHz with low-distortion, low-power and low-voltage options.


National Semiconductor Analog
――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――
Description
National Semiconductor analog ICs.

This collection provides a range of analog ICs across a variety of categories, including:
  • Voltage regulators
  • Line drivers/receivers
  • Power detectors
  • Microcontrollers
  • Multiplexers
  • Codecs/filters
  • Amplifiers
  • Timers
  • Decoders


National Semiconductor Audio
――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――
Description
National Semiconductor audio-specific ICs.

This collection features a range of audio-specific ICs such as speaker and headphone amplifiers, noise suppression, integrated
audio subsystems, and automotive audio solutions.


National Semiconductor Communication
――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――
Description
National Semiconductor low-power PLLs.

The LMC568 device featured in this collection is an amplitude-linear phase-locked loop consisting of a linear VCO, fully balanced phase
detectors, and a carrier detect output. LMCMOS technology is employed for high performance with low power consumption.
The VCO has a linearized control range of ±30% to allow demodulation of FM and FSK signals. Carrier detect is indicated when the PLL
is locked to an input signal greater than 26mVrms. LMC568 applications include FM SCA and TV second audio program decoders, FSK data
demodulators, and voice pagers.
Device features:
  • Demodulates ±15% deviation FM/FSK signals
  • Carrier Detect Output with hysteresis
  • Operation to 500kHz input frequency
  • Low THD-0.5% typ. for ±10% deviation
  • 2V to 9V supply voltage range
  • Low supply current drain


National Semiconductor Comparator
――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――
Description
National Semiconductor comparator ICs.

This collection offers a range of single, dual and quad comparator devices, with low-power and low-voltage options. Outputs include
Open-Drain, Push-Pull, and RSPECL.


National Semiconductor DAC
――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――
Description
National Semiconductor D/A Converters (DACs).

This collection provides Digital to Analog Converters ranging from 1 to 8 channels, 8- to 16-bit, with both SPI and I2C interfaces.


National Semiconductor Interface
――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――
Description
National Semiconductor interface ICs.

This collection provides a range of interface ICs suited to a variety of applications. Devices are available across a variety of
categories, including:
  • Ethernet Transceivers
  • LVDS drivers and receivers
  • SerDes Data and Video
  • RS (RS-232, 422/23, etc)
  • PHYs/LVDS
  • SCAN/JTAG
  • UARTS
  • USB
  • Signal conditioning repeaters and buffers
  • SDI/SMPTE Deserializers/Serializers/cable drivers
  • Display solutions
  • Clock/Timing/Keyscanning


National Semiconductor LDO
――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――
Description
National Semiconductor Low Dropout Regulators (LDOs).

National Semiconductor's broad portfolio of low-noise, low-power low-dropout (LDO) regulators preserve signal fidelity in the analog
signal path over a wide range of input voltages and output currents. LDOs are offered in a variety of packages from the industry
standard SOIC to LLP and Micro SMD to achieve the smallest footprint, or the TO-263 for best thermal dissipation.


National Semiconductor MiscPower
――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――
Description
National Semiconductor miscellaneous power ICs.

This collection features a wide range of power-related ICs, focusing on areas such as power management (chargers, power converters,
multi-output regulators, power controllers, buck voltage converters, voltage references), automotive and video applications,
amplifiers, drivers, and many more.


National Semiconductor OtherParts
――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――
Description
National Semiconductor – various ICs.

This collection offers a mixed selection of ICs, covering areas such as:
  • Amplifiers
  • Audio
  • Controllers
  • DSPs
  • Interface ICs
  • Logic
  • Power Management
  • RF/IF
  • Sensors
  • Video


National Semiconductor Switch Caps
――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――
Description
National Semiconductor switched-capacitor power management ICs.

This collection offers a selection of switched-capacitor power ICs covering charge pumps, DC-DC converters, LED drivers, power
controllers and regulators.


National Semiconductor Switcher
――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――
Description
National Semiconductor power management ICs including Switching Regulators.

This collection offers a selection of power management and interface ICs including:
  • DC-DC converters
  • LED drivers
  • MOSFET drivers
  • Power controllers
  • RGB drivers
  • SMPS controllers
  • Switching regulators
  • Transistor drivers
  • Voltage regulators
  • USB controllers


National Semiconductor Temperature Sensor
――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――
Description
National Semiconductor temperature sensor ICs.

This collection offers a range of temperature sensor ICs available in digital and analog, Celsius and Fahrenheit. Devices are
available across the following categories:
  • Thermal window comparators
  • Thermostat ICs
  • Remote diodes
  • Thermal watchdogs
  • Resistor-programmable temperature switches


National Semiconductor Voltage Reference
――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――
Description
National Semiconductor voltage reference ICs.

This collection offers a selection of voltage reference ICs including:
  • Reference diodes
  • Adjustable voltage reference ICs
  • Shunt voltage references
  • Low dropout voltage references with ultra-high precision micropower options
