NXP Semiconductors
════════════════════════════════════════════════════════════════

NXP Semiconductors Cortex-M0
――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――
Description
NXP Cortex-M0 32-bit ARM microcontrollers.

ARM Cortex-M0 is a low-cost alternative for 8/16-bit designs. The LPC1100XL series offers industry-leading low-cost and low-power
consumption, in low-pin-count packages, including the LPC1102, the world’s smallest 32-bit ARM MCU. The LPC11A00 microcontroller
series features a fully interconnected and flexible analog subsystem which can provide seamless integration of various analog blocks
and off-load the CPU from critical tasks. The LPC11C00 series is the first CAN microcontroller and transceiver with CANopen drivers.
The LPC11D00 series is capable of driving Liquid Crystal Displays, and can be cascaded to accommodate up to 2560 segments for larger
display applications. The LPC11U00 delivers robust USB performance at a low price point. The LPC11E00 is a feature rich solution with
up to 4K EEPROM for space-constrained applications such as medical and industrial measuring devices. The LPC1200 series, NXP’s latest
generation of Cortex-M0, delivers high energy efficiency and includes specific features for industrial control.


NXP Semiconductors Cortex-M3
――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――
Description
NXP Cortex-M3 32-bit ARM microcontrollers.

ARM Cortex-M3's are high-performance MCUs designed for use with communications and control. The LPC1300, a low-power, low-cost
implementation, performs USB device functions. The LPC1700 integrates advanced peripherals, such as Ethernet, USB 2.0, and CAN 2.0B.
The LPC1800, the highest-performing Cortex-M3 available on the market, operates at up to 180MHz and offers up to 1MB of Flash and up
to 200KB of SRAM.


NXP Semiconductors Cortex-M4
――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――
Description
NXP Cortex-M4 32-bit ARM microcontrollers.

ARM Cortex-M4's extend ARM MCUs with high performance digital signal processing capabilities. Consuming less power, and offering
more peripherals, the LPC4300 series is the world’s first family of asymmetrical, dual-core digital signal controllers (DSCs).
