Maxim
════════════════════════════════════════════════════════════════

Maxim Amplifiers and Comparators
――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――
Description
Maxim operational amplifiers, current-sense amplifiers and comparators for signal conditioning, monitoring and control applications.
This collection includes the following devices:
  • High-Efficiency Dual Op Amps with Zero-Drift and Rail to Rail IO
  • Precision Current-Sense Amplifier
  • Ultra-Precision, Low-Noise Op Amp
  • Precision, Low-Noise, Wide-Band Amplifiers
  • High-Side, Current-Sense Amplifier with 12-Bit ADC and Op Amp/Comparator
  • Low-Power, High-Efficiency, Single/Dual, Rail-to-Rail I/O Op Amps
  • Ultra-Small, Low-Power Single Comparators


Maxim Analog Switches and Multiplexers
――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――
Description
Maxim low-on-resistance, high-performance analog switches and multiplexers.
This collection includes the following devices:
  • Above and Below the Rails Low On-Resistance Analog Switches
  • Dual +/-25V Above and Below the Rails 4:1 Analog Multiplexers
  • USB Device Charger Detectors


Maxim Data Converters
――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――
Description
Maxim analog-to-digital converters (ADCs) and digital-to-analog converters (DACs)
This collection includes the following devices:
  • 16-Bit, +5V, 200ksps ADCs with 10uA Shutdown
  • 3Msps, Low-Power, Serial 10/12-Bit, 16/8-Channel ADCs
  • 14/16-Bit, Low-Power, High-Performance, Buffered Single DACs


Maxim Hot-Swap, PoE and Power Switching
――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――
Description
This collection currently contains Maxim power switching products with the following devices:
  • Dual 1.2A Programmable-Current USB Switches with Autoreset
  • Single 1.2A USB Switches
  • Automotive Qualified, Single 1.2A USB Switches


Maxim Interface, Interconnect and Signal Integrity
――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――
Description
This collection currently contains a selection of Maxim UART devices:
  • Quad Serial UART with 128-word FIFO
  • SPI/I²C UART with 128-word FIFO
  • Dual Serial UART with 128-word FIFO


Maxim Memory
――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――
Description
Maxim 1-Wire memory, nonvolatile (NV) SRAM and nonvolatile (NV) RAM controllers.

1-Wire devices provide combinations of memory, mixed-signal, and secure authentication functions through a single-contact serial
interface. Power is derived from the signal bus (parasitically) and a single line can support multiple devices. Each device has
a unique factory-lasered ID.
Nonvolatile (NV) SRAM devices deliver fast reads/writes and the endurance of SRAM with the convenience of nonvolatile memory.
Both DIP and PowerCap modules are available, with a range of memory sizes up to 16MB.
Nonvolatile (NV) RAM Controllers convert CMOS RAM into nonvolatile memory while optionally integrating time keeping functions.
Features:
   • All have chip enable
   • Available in SmartSocket with internal battery or lithium battery monitors
   • Can control 1 to 16 NV RAMs
   • Work with 2Kx8 up to 128Kx8 memory configurations


Maxim Microcontroller
――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――
Description
Maxim low-power, secure and general-purpose microcontrollers.

Maxim's low-power 16-bit MAXQ RISC microcontrollers are efficient, high-performance MCUs for battery-powered embedded systems.
Features across the device range include:
  • Core clock speeds up to 20MHz
  • Up to 128KB of internal Flash
  • Up to 6KB internal SRAM
  • Up to 55 GPIO pins
  • Varying communication interfaces depending on device chosen – USART, SPI, I2C, IR, USB
Maxim's ultra-secure 8-bit microcontrollers secure and protect data and valuable IP. They include FIPS-compliant hardware cryptographic
engines and random number generators, as well as fast-erase nonvolatile (NV) SRAM, which is erased instantly when an intrusion is
detected. Also included are a variety of temper-detection mechanisms, and real-time encryption for external code and data memories.
Features across the device range include:
  • Core clock speed up to 16MHz
  • Up to 0.25KB internal SRAM
  • 32 GPIO pins
  • 1 USART
Maxim's general-purpose 8- and 16-bit microcontrollers offer an array of embedded peripherals, memory sizes, and architectures for a
broad range of applications. Features across the device range include:
  • Core clock speeds up to 75MHz
  • Up to 128KB of internal Flash
  • Up to 64KB internal SRAM
  • Up to 55 GPIO pins
  • Varying communication interfaces depending on device chosen – USART, SPI, I²C, IR, USB


Maxim Power and Battery Management
――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――
Description
Maxim power and battery management devices.

Currently this collection contains a wide range of battery chargers, capacitor charge pumps, DC-DC switching regulators, isolated
power supplies, linear regulators and MOSFET drivers.


Maxim Real-Time Clocks (RTCs)
――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――
Description
This collection of Maxim real-time clocks contains:
  • MEMS based Real-Time Clocks with I2C Interface
  • Low-Current I2C Real-Time Clocks for High-ESR Crystals
  • Low-Current SPI/3-Wire Real-Time Clocks


Maxim Sensors
――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――
Description
The Maxim sensors collection contains a selection of programmable resolution digital thermometers with 1-wire interface, high-precision
DS75 compatible digital thermometer and thermostats, low voltage digital temperature sensors with 2-wire interface, digital thermometer
and thermostats with SPI/3-wire interface and ±1°C accurate 8-channel temperature sensors.


Maxim Supervisors, Voltage Monitors and Sequencers
――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――――
Description
This contains a wide range of Maxim's microprocessor supervisory solutions including:
  • 125nA Supervisory Circuits with Capacitor-Adjustable Reset and Watchdog Timeouts
  • Low-Power, 1% Accurate, Single/Dual/Triple/Quad LBO output Level Battery Monitors
  • Battery-Backup Circuits with Regulated Output Voltage
  • High-Voltage, Adjustable Sequencing/Supervisory Circuits
  • Load-Dump/Reverse-Voltage Protection Circuits, limiter-mode fault management
  • Low-Voltage, Hex/Octal-Voltage uP Supervisors
  • On/Off Controllers with Debounce and +/-15kV ESD Protection
